harvestpublicmedia.org 2012-06-12

# Harvest's Privacy Policy | Harvest Public Media

Effective: 10/1/10

This Privacy Policy explains Harvestpublicmedia.org’s position on information gathering and how we intend to use and share any information we collect. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by Harvestpublicmedia.org and does not apply to information obtained or used by Harvest Public Media or its affiliates through other means.

**You understand and agree that, by visiting Harvestpublicmedia.org you are accepting, without modification, this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any portion of this Privacy Policy, then your only option is to not use Harvestpublicmedia.org.**

This Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time by Harvestpublicmedia.org and your continued use of Harvestpublicmedia.org means you agree to, without modification, the revisions. If you are a registered memberof Harvestpublicmedia.org, you will be notified of material revisions to this Privacy Policy via an e-mail message to the e-mail address that you provided at registration. If you are not a registered member of Harvestpublicmedia.org, you may view revisions to this Privacy Policy on this page. Material changes to this Privacy Policy will be indicated by a revised effective date at the top left hand corner of this page. Whether or not you are a registered member of Harvestpublicmedia.org, it is your responsibility to check back and review this page regularly to ensure you are familiar with the most current terms. Should you object to any such modifications to this Privacy Policy or become dissatisfied with Harvestpublicmedia.org. in any way, your only option is to immediately terminate your membership and discontinue use of Harvestpublicmedia.org. Otherwise, continuing to use the service after the effective date means that you agree to be bound by the changes, without modification.

**Information we collect**

Member registration may require you to provide your e-mail address. All users may decline to share this information with us, by choosing not to register on Harvestpublicmedia.org or not to use our services. Only registered members, however, may offer commentary.

If you wish to forward an article to a friend, we will ask that you provide your friend's name and e-mail address. While we may collect statistics on which articles are forwarded, we do not sell, rent, or market your friend's personal information.

**Passive data collection and use**

Like most web sites, Harvestpublicmedia.org also collects and logs information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to you, such as your IP address, the name and location of your Internet Service Provider, the type and version of your browser, the length of time that you stay on Harvestpublicmedia.org, search queries, your click-stream data, the location that referred you to Harvestpublicmedia.org and the average number of pages viewed. If you visit another Web site prior to browsing Harvestpublicmedia.org, that web site might place personally identifiable information within a URL, which may be logged by us. Your IP address is the identifier assigned to your particular computer when you access the internet. Depending on how you connect to the internet, your IP address may always be the same, or it may change each time you access the internet. Note that logging your IP address does not in and of itself provide us with your name, e-mail address or home or work address. We use this log information for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes and may also use it to gather general demographic information about you such as your general location and your Internet Service Provider.

**Use of cookies**

Most standard Web browsers contain a feature called "cookies," which allow a Web site to place information about a user's visit to that Web site in a small data text file that is stored on the user's computer. Our use of cookie technology will likely be transparent to you and is used to recognize you and hold information from one visit to the next in an effort to increase your ease of use of Harvestpublicmedia.org and to allow us to better understand how people use Harvestpublicmedia.org through click-stream analysis. For example, cookies may be used to store information such as your member name and password, sparing you from having to re-enter that information each time you visit. You can turn the cookies feature off by using your browser preference options.

**Use of personally identifiable information**

Personally identifiable information may be accessed by the user who entered it, by Harvest Public Media personnel, and by certain third parties, such as those who provide technical support or content services to Harvestpublicmedia.org.

We may also disclose personally identifiable information when deemed necessary or appropriate:

  * to comply with a subpoena or other service of process, court order, or other legal proceeding, or if otherwise requested by a legitimate law enforcement body to cooperate in their investigations;
  * to otherwise comply with applicable law;
  * to prevent, investigate, or to take some other action against illegal activities, potential fraud, potential physical threats to any person, or as required by law;
  * to comply with part of the sale or transfer of business assets, if we sell all or a part of our business;
  * to protect the rights, property, or safety of Harvestpublicmedia.org, its affiliates or others.

**Use of aggregated information**

To describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and others, we may use your personally identifiable information to create a compiled, aggregate and anonymous view of the Harvestpublicmedia.org audience and their usage patterns ("Aggregated Information"). We use Aggregated Information to operate our services and to better understand our audience as we develop new content and services.

**Member mail and e-mail offers**

Harvestpublicmedia.org does not rent, sell, barter or give away its user or member lists or its users' or members' e-mail addresses for use by advertisers and other third parties for the purpose of solicitations.

**Deleting your account**

You can delete your Harvestpublicmedia.org membership account by emailing [accounts@harvestpublicmedia.org](mailto:accounts@harvestpublicmedia.org).  In the subject line please write: Account Termination.  Please include your username in the body of the email.  Failure to follow both of these steps may limit our ability to cancel your account in a timely manner.  By canceling your account, all but a transactional record of your membership account will be removed from our databases, though some records may remain on back-up media. Note that by deleting your account, you may no longer be able to post comments.

**Remember the risks when you use the Internet**

You should know that when you voluntarily disclose personal information on the Harvestpublicmedia.org Web site (for example, in the discussion forums), that information can be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages from other people. While we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot be responsible for information that you choose to publicly disclose. Further, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. Although we make good faith efforts to store the information we collect in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public and to work with responsible third parties, we cannot guarantee complete security for your information.

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions or comments about our policies, we may be reached at Harvest Public Media, 4325 Troost, Suite 202, Kansas City, Mo., 62110; 816-235-2828 or email [accounts@harvestpublicmedia.org](mailto:accounts@harvestpublicmedia.org).
